哈哈  玉米片耳环  我真滑稽
Ha ha! Nacho earrings! I'm hilarious!
这说法有待商榷
That's debatable.
噢  拜托  这交通是怎么了
Aw, come on. What's with all this traffic?
而且为什么到处都是
And why is it all...
带棚马车
Covered wagons?!
噢  不
Oh, no!
不  不
No! No!
不要是今天  不要是今天
Not today! Not today!
-噢  老天爷啊  -我的神啊
-Oh, heavens! -Goodness!
斯坦叔公  怎么了
Grunkle Stan, what's going on?
我们必须马上离开这儿  不然就太晚了
We gotta get out of here... Before it's too late!
他们用马车绕成了一个圈  我们被包围了
They've circled the wagons! We're trapped!
不要啊
No!!!
我觉得今天会过得很不错
I got a good feeling about today.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： shortcut
翻译： 舜小希
■
校订： 萌小懒  WaitinZ
后期： WaitinZ  liloelva
怪诞小镇  第一季第八集
Gravity Falls  S01E08  Irrational Treasure
天哪  看看镇上
Man. Look at the town.
脏玻璃  我们有脏玻璃
Dirty glass! We got dirty glass!
- 脏玻璃  - 啊天哪
- Dirty glass. - Aw, boy.
今天是先驱者日
It's pioneer day.
每年这些家伙都会穿得像白痴一样
Every year these yahoos dress up like idiots
来庆祝重力泉成立的日子
To celebrate the day Gravity Falls was founded.
欢迎来到1863年
Welcome to 1863!
当心我揍你  小矮子
I will break you, little man!
哇  看  浸制蜡烛
Wow, look! Candle dipping!
哇  淘金
Whoa! Gold panning!
我现在宣布你们结为夫妻
I now pronounce you man and wife.
我愿意
I do!
你在瞎说什么啊
What you talkin' about?
噢  是的  我想起来了
Oh, yeah, I remember this.
在重力泉  和啄木鸟结婚曾经是合法的
In Gravity Falls it used to be legal to marry woodpeckers.
噢  这仍然是合法的  相当合法
Oh, it's still legal... Very legal.
大家都来参加开幕式吧
Come one and all for the opening ceremonies!
-斯坦叔公  你一起来吗  -我才不去呢
-Grunkle Stan, you comin'? -No thank you!
记好了  如果你们回到小屋时
Just remember if you come back to the shack
说话和这些家伙一个腔调  你们就找死吧
Talking like these people, you're dead to me!
萝卜窖里有一个投机者
Thar's a carpetbagger in the turnip cellar!
啊  去摇摇摇我的干粮袋吧
Well, hornswaggle my haversack!
找死
Dead to me!!!
听得见吗  听得见吗
Hear ye, hear ye!
古老而有趣的庆祝典礼马上就要开始了
Ye olde commencement ceremony is about to commence.
呜呼  我有铃铛咯
Whoo! I got a bell!
噢  不  警官  我的钱包
Oh, no! Police! My purse!
叮叮  当当  呜呼
Ring ring! Ring ring! Hoo!
他还真是爱他的铃铛啊
He sure loves his bell.
大家好
Howdy, everyone.
你们都认识我  我是帕西菲卡・诺斯维斯特
You all know me, Pacifica Northwest,
小镇创立者纳撒尼尔・诺斯维斯特的重重孙女
Great-great-granddaughter of town founder Nathaniel Northwest.
而且我还很有钱
I'm also very rich.
现在  如果你有先驱者精神的话
Now, if you've got the pioneer spirit,
我们将邀请你上台介绍自己
We ask you to come on up and introduce yourself.
观众互动环节耶
Audience participation!
我不明白  梅宝  那个女孩儿不是你的死敌吗
I don't know, Mabel. Isn't that girl kind of like your arch enemy?
那都是过去的事儿了
That's water under the bridge.
我们的第一个新人是
Our first newcomer is...
梅宝
Mabel.
是的  让我们开始庆祝先驱者日吧
Yeah! Let's this pioneer day started!
对不对  大家伙儿
Right, guys?
美利坚  美利坚
USA! USA!
不好意思打断你一下  但先驱者日是属于正经人的
I'm sorry to break it to you, but pioneer day is for serious people,
可是你的外表和行为都很荒诞
And you look and act ridiculous.
我是说  一只玩篮球的狗狗
I mean, a puppy playing basketball?
你总是这么傻气吗
Are you always this silly?
嘿  我可以很正经的
Hey! I can be serious!
你耳朵上正挂着玉米片耳环啊  亲爱的
You do have nachos hanging from your ears, hon.
哇  我真替你害臊
Wow, I'm embarrassed for you.
鼓励一下她吧  大家伙儿
Give her a hand, everybody!
现在  谁想听我接着说我自己
Now, who wants to hear more about me?
借过一下
Excuse me.
大家一起说  诺斯维斯特
Everyone say, "Northwest."
诺斯维斯特
Northwest.
我们真完美
We're perfect.
嘿  你还好吗
Hey, you okay?
我需要一些过期的奶油糖
I need some old-timey butterscotch.
我们离开这儿吧
Let's get out of here.
嘿  你好
Hey, there.
放驴娃  帮我修修车  怎么样
Donkey boy. Give me a hand with my car, huh?
现在是1863年  我从来没有听说过车
Here in 1863 I have never heard tell of a... Car.
请告诉我  这个神奇的带轮子的盒子是个什么玩意儿
Pray tell, what is this magic wheel box?
啊  得了吧  史蒂夫  看在老天爷的份上  你是一个技工啊
Ach! Come on, Steve, you're a mechanic, for Pete's sake.
你饶了我吧
Cut me some slack!
“饶” 我不知道这个新新词汇呢
"Slack." I am unfamiliar with this bold new expression.
我受不了了
I can't take this anymore!
在这儿每多待一秒我就变得更蠢一点儿
I'm getting dumber every second I'm here!
这儿需要我们干预一下吗
Are we gonna have to intervene here?
噢  看哪  是警官
Oh, look... The constable.
你要干什么  把我锁在手枷里吗
What are you gonna do, throw me in "ye stocks"?
噢  不是吧
Aw, come on!
嘿  造型不错  吉迪恩
Hey, nice outfit, Gideon.
你看起来真的没有原来那么娘了
You actually look less girly than usual.
怎么说呢  斯坦福德  我只是一个卖西红柿的卑微的农民
Why, Stanford, I'm just a humble tomato farmer sellin' his wares.
哎哟  我丢了一个
Whoops! I dropped one!
我又丢了一个
I dropped another one.
先驱者日
Pioneer day!!!
迪普  我能问你一件事吗
Dipper, can I ask you something?
你觉得我  傻么
Do you think i'm... Silly?
呃  不觉得啊
Uh, noooo.
噢  我就知道
Ohh! I knew it!
玉米片耳环  还有这毛衣
The nacho earrings, the sweater...
我还以为我迷人得很呢
I thought I was being charming,
但我想其他人都把我看成一个大笑话吧
But I guess people see me as a big joke.
好啦  梅宝  你喜欢这件毛衣啊
Come on, Mabel. You love that sweater.
在帕西菲卡毁了它之前我确实喜欢
I did before Pacifica ruined it for me.
她总是把一切都毁了
She ruins everything.
帕西菲卡
Pacifica!
她为什么觉得和小镇创立者有关系
Why Doe she think that being related to the town founder
就可以像对待废物一样对待其他人呢
Means she gets to treat everyone like garbage?
有人得好好教训教训她
Someone needs to take her down a peg.
等等  我感觉我以前读到过
Wait a minute! I feel like I read something
关于帕西菲卡曾曾祖父的东西
About Pacifica's great-great-grandfather before.
当然了  噢  这真是太棒了
Of course! Oh, this is perfect.
在我的调查过程中
"In my investigations..."
我应该用这种声音吗
Should I do the voice?
-不用了不用了  -我就正常地读吧
-Unh-unh.  -i'll just read normal.
在我的调查过程中  我有了一个新的发现
"In my investigations I recently made a discovery.
纳撒尼尔・诺斯维斯特也许并不是重力泉的创建者
"Nathaniel Northwest may not be the founder of Gravity Falls.
我相信这个秘密的证据被埋在
"I believe the proof of this secret is buried
这个附件所提到的某个地方
"somewhere on the enclosed document.
要是我能解开密码就好了
If only I could crack the code."
噢  天哪  如果这件被掩盖的事是真的
Oh, man! If this cover-up is true,
那么帕西菲卡一家人就都是骗子
It means Pacifica's whole family is a fraud!
这可能是一个巨大的阴谋
This could be a major conspiracy!
-真的吗  -我得去调查这件事
-Really? -I gotta investigate this!
等等  我和你一起去
Wait. I'm coming with you.
-阴谋是一件正经事  对吧  -噢  是的  当然了
-Conspiracies are serious, right? -Oh, yeah, definitely.
好吧  如果我帮你破了密码
Well, if I help you crack this code,
再也不会有人说我傻了
Nobody could ever call me silly again!
好啊  解密二人组
Yeah! Mystery twins?
我以为你讨厌这个名字
I thought you hated that.
我正在努力接受它
I'm starting to accept it.
我是布拉布斯警长  我们遇到了密码问题
This is Sheriff Blubs. We've got a code sepia.
什么  那你们准备怎么做
What?! And what are you doing about it?
我现在正跟着他们呢
I'm following them right now.
找到他们  赶紧阻止  不允许出任何差错
Find them and stop them. There's no room for error.
我懂了  布拉布斯挂了
I understand. Blubs out.
杜兰德副警长  我们训练了一辈子
Deputy Durland, maintaining this cover-up
就是为了掩盖这件事
Is the mission we've been training for our entire careers.
-你准备好了吗  -呜呼
-Are you ready?  -Whoo!
如果快乐是一种罪行的话  你已经违法了
If being delightful was a crime, you'd be breaking the law.
让我们去抓住他们吧
Let's go get 'em!
在过去
Back in the old days,
先驱者们通过在火堆边讲故事混饭
pioneers drew sustenance from telling stories around the fire.
所以我们来吃点书吧  孩子们
So let's eat some books, children.
来吧  吃点书
Go ahead, eat the books!
好了  梅宝  如果我们能证明纳撒尼尔・诺斯维斯特
All right, Mabel. If we can prove that Nathaniel Northwest
不是重力泉的真正创建者
Wasn't the real founder of Gravity Falls,
那帕西菲卡就能安分守己了
It'll finally put Pacifica in her place.
而且解开谜题还能证明我根本不傻
And solving a mystery will prove that I'm not silly,
我是正经的
I'm serious!
正经的
Seriousss...
我们只需要破解这个密码
We just need to crack this code.
让我想想
Let me see...
不是埃及语
It's not Egyptian,
不是数字命理
It's not numerology,
不是  等一下  当然了
It's not... Wait! Of course!
三角形是炼金术师表示火焰的符号
The triangle is the alchemist's symbol for flame.
点燃羊皮纸就能解开密码了
Lighting the parchment on fire will reveal the secret message!
这真是太明显了
It's so obvious!
好吧  我们来把这玩意儿点燃
All right. Let's just light this sucker up and...
-梅宝  -哇  我折了顶帽子
-Mabel! -wop! I just made a hat!
啊  我又干傻事了
Achh! I just did something silly again!
等等  梅宝  你把它折成了一张地图
Wait. Mabel, you folded it into a map.
而我差点就把它烧了
And I was gonna burn it.
我们在寻找两个孩子
We were on the lookout for two kids
他们也许在这儿读书
Who might be reading.
我们因为秘密的原因而追捕他们  呜呼
We're hunting 'em down for secret reasons. Whoo!
也许我们应该把它带到别的地方去
Maybe we should take this elsewhere.
这张地图会把我们带到
This map should lead us to...
重力泉历史博物馆
The Gravity Falls Museum of History.
你知道这代表着什么吗  梅宝
You realize what this means, Mabel.
我们得硬闯进去
We're gonna have to break in.
这是你们的先驱者日免费通行证
And those are your free pioneer day passes
还有你们的气球  蓝色的和粉色的
And your balloons, blue and pink.
我们闯进来了
We're in.
我们下一步做什么
What are we gonna do next?
去偷托马斯・杰斐逊的胸腔吗
Steal Thomas Jefferson's rib cage?
真恶心  当然不是  根据地图
Ew. No. According to the map,
关于小镇真正创立者的下一条线索应该就在  这儿
The next clue about the real town founder should be right... Here!
我们得快点解开这条线索
We have to figure this one out quick.
我觉得那些警察并不是去图书馆借书的
I have a feeling those cops weren't at the library to check out books.
我觉得那个带着铃铛的根本不认识字
I don't think the one with the bell can read.
那这到底是什么
So what is it, anyway?
嘿  你这个图  别这么傻
Hey, painting. Be less stupid.
-这句话管用了  -什么
-It worked!  -Huh?
等等  这不是抽象画  它只是颠倒了
Wait! It's not abstract, it's upside-down!
我觉得我在墓地见过这个雕塑
I think i've seen that statue in the cemetery.
我们走吧  快
Let's go! Quick!
嗷嗷嗷  啊嗷  头晕了
Ow ow ow! Ahh! Ow! Head rush.
不好意思  我们没有粉色气球了
I'm sorry, but we're all out of pink balloons.
那我们还来干嘛
Why did we even come?
布拉布斯警官
Officer Blubs.
布拉布斯在此
Blubs here.
目标对象已经逮捕了吗
Have the targets been apprehended?
还没有  不过快了
Negative. But we're close.
我保证  那俩孩子绝不会从我们身边逃走的
I promise, those kids'll never get past us.
嘿  等等
Hey! Wait!
该死的
Dang it!
我最后一次重申
For the last time,
我们不去南方过冬
We are not going south for the winter!
我们的家在这儿
Our home is here!
你总这么说
You always say that!
加油
Come on...
加油  啊
Come on. Aah!
呀  这不是梅宝的叔公  派恩斯先生么
Well, if it isn't Mabel's uncle, Mr. Pines.
-你在找这个吗  -是的  是的
-Looking for this? -Yeah, yeah.
你想要什么  钱吗
What do you want, money?
我想要你说诺斯维斯特家族
I want you to say that the Northwest family
是重力泉最好的家族
Is the best family in Gravity Falls.
噢  没问题  你想让我写下来吗
Oh, sure. You want that in writing?
好了
There we go.
你去死！
哈  我用嘴巴写成的噢
Ha! I did that with my mouth!
噢  别这样
Oh, come on!
雕塑一定指示着下一条线索
The statue must be pointing to the next clue.
噢  真棒  她在抠我的鼻子呢  哈哈
Oh, cool! She's picking my nose! Ha ha!
梅宝  你看
Mabel, look!
哈  现在是谁傻  帕西菲卡  哦耶
Ha! Who's silly now, Pacifica? Bam!
啊  嗷嗷嗷  好了
Ahh! Ow. Ow. Ow. Okay.
现在我们正式进入阴谋模式了
Now we're getting into real conspiracy mode.
我感觉好正经啊
I feel serious.
好吧  小心有陷阱
Okay, look out for Booby traps.
哈  陷阱
Ha! Booby traps.
镇静剂飞镖  啊
Tranquilizer darts! Aah!
是古老的秘密地下宝藏
It's a treasure trove of historic-y, secret-y things.
绝密
林肯的帽子
总统的掩饰
绝密
本杰明・富兰克林
其实是个女的
噢  天哪
Oh, man!
本・富兰克林其实真是个女人
Ben Franklin secretly was a woman.
嘿  找到了
Hey, jackpot!
诺斯维斯特家族掩藏的秘密
绝密
现在我们就能知道谁是真正的小镇创建者了
Now we'll find out who the real town founder was.
兹记录纳撒尼尔・诺斯维斯特
"Let it be here recorded that Nathaniel Northwest,
传说中的重力泉创建者
"fabled founder of Gravity Falls,
其实是一个骗子
"was, in fact, a fraud,
他只是一个在村里铲垃圾的白痴
As well as a waste-shoveling village idiot."
对帕西菲卡来说  真是个坏消息啊
Oh, bad news for Pacifica.
等着看报纸报道这个吧
Wait'll the papers hear about this!
一旦人们知道是我揭开了这个历史阴谋
Once people see that I uncovered a historical conspiracy,
他们再也不会说我傻了
They could never call me silly!
真正的重力泉创建者
"The true founder of Gravity Falls
是昆廷・特朗布莱三世先生
Was sir lord, Quentin Trembley, III, Esquire."
谁是昆廷・特朗布莱
Who's Quentin Trembley?
这不关你们的事
That's none of your business!
呜呼  抓到你们了
Whoo! We gotcha!
他被好几个飞镖击中了
He got hit with quite a few of those darts.
我不想说  但是昆廷・特朗布莱和国家安全有关
I hate to do this but Quentin Trembley's a matter of national security.
是的  是的  呜呼
Yeah! Yeah... Whoo...
我觉得我好像变成色盲了
I think I might be colorblind now.
国家安全  什么意思
What do you mean, national security?
另外昆廷・特朗布莱到底是谁啊
And who is Quentin Trembley, anyway?
自己看看吧
See for yourself.
啊  黑白的啊
Ahh, black and white?!
美国政府
嘘  梅宝
Shh! Mabel.
绝密
如果你看到了这个
If you're watching this,
那么你就是全美国
Then you are one of eight people in these United States
被许可观看这条信息的八人之一
with clearance to view this information.
事实上  等这部片子完工后  我将会被射杀
In fact, I myself will be shot as soon as the filming is complete.
什么  不会吗  哈  好吧  真是让我松了口气
What? No? Ha! Well, that's a relief!
在美国的所有秘密当中
Of all of America's secrets,
最让人害臊的当属昆廷・特朗布莱了
The most embarrassing was that of Quentin Trembley.
他是美国第八任半总统
The eighth-and-a-half president of the United States.
总统  第八任半
President?! Eighth-and-a-half?!
在以压倒性优势赢得1837年的竞选后
After winning the 1837 election in a landslide,
（注：字面意思为“在滑坡中”）
昆廷・特朗布莱很快获得了
Quentin Trembley quickly gained a reputation
美国最傻总统的名声
As America's silliest president.
他向薄煎饼宣战  任命六个婴儿为最高法院大法官
He waged war on pancakes, appointed six babies to the supreme court,
并发表了反裤子解放宣言
And issued the de-pants-ipation proclamation.
他的国情咨文演讲更是一团糟
His state of the union speech was even worse.
我们唯一应该恐惧的事物
The only thing we have to fear
（注：源自富兰克林・罗斯福著名演讲词
“唯一能令我们恐惧的东西，就是恐惧本身”）
就是巨大的食人蜘蛛
Is gigantic, man-eating spiders!
他被赶出办公室后
He was kicked out of office
逃到了一个不为人知的村庄
And escaped to an uncharted valley
他将其命名为重力泉
He named Gravity Falls,
就在他以迅雷不及掩耳之势闯进去之后
After plummeting into it at high speed.
特朗布莱丢人的任期在历史上被抹去了
Trembley's shameful term was erased from history
威廉・亨利・哈里森正式取代了他的总统职位
And officially replaced by William Henry Harrison as president
同时一个无名小卒也取代了他  被当做重力泉的创立者
And local nobody as founder of Gravity Falls.
但特朗布莱总统的尸体却下落不明
The whereabouts of president Trembley's body are unknown.
直到现在
Until now.
那是琥珀还是什么吗
Is that, like, amber or something?
那个蠢货以为他这样能长生不老
The fool thought he could live forever
他把自己包裹在一个大花生硬糖里了
By encasing himself in a block of solid peanut brittle.
好聪明  总统先生
Smooth move, Mr. President!
找到特朗布莱的尸体一直是我们的特殊任务
Finding Trembley's body was our special mission.
现在呢  拜你们所赐  我们完成了
And now, thanks to you, it's complete.
谁会知道我们仅仅是
Who knew all we had to do
跟着一个小姑娘沿路丢下的糖果纸呢
Was follow a little girl's trail of candy wrappers?
噢  我太傻了
Ohh, silly!
既然你们知道真相了
Now that you know the truth,
我们可不能让你们到处瞎说
Well, we can't let you go around talkin' about it.
你的意思是  你要杀了我们吗
Does that mean... Are you gonna kill us?!
噢  不是  不会  不会
Oh, no! No, no.
放轻松  伙计  放轻松
Calm down now, buddy, calm down.
我们只是要护送你们和这玩意儿回到华盛顿
We're just gonna escort you and all this stuff back to Washington.
顺便说一句  你们不能再回来了
You ain't comin' back, by the way.
呜呼  我们有折叠床
Whoo-hoo! We got fold-out beds!
好消息  我带了恐怖鬼故事书
Good thing I brought my book of spooky ghost stories!
我带了做友谊腕带的绳子
I brought rope for friendship bracelets!
有人吗  救命啊
Anyone there?! Help!
嘿  让我们出去
Hey! Let us out!
噢  我不敢相信我竟然丢了一路的糖果纸
Ohh. I can't believe I left a trail of candy wrappers.
这全是我的错
This is all my fault.
帕西菲卡对我的评价一直都是对的
Pacifica had me pegged all along.
我就是一个傻气的废物
I'm just a silly failure,
就像这个丢脸的什么什么总统
Like that embarrassing president what's-his-name.
是我  我是昆廷・特朗布莱
It is I, Quentin Trembley.
你还活着  你怎么做到的
You're alive! But how?
花生硬糖真的有延续生命的功效啊
Peanut brittle really does have life-sustaining properties!
你不傻  你太聪明了
You're not silly, you're brilliant!
你也是  小姑娘
And so are you, dear girl,
因为你根据我的线索把我从这美味的坟墓里解放出来了
For following my clues and freeing me from my delicious tomb!
他是对的  把地图折成帽子  颠倒着看画
He's right! Making maps into hats, hanging upside-down;
你的傻正好解开了密码
Your silliness solved the code
那些正经的警察花了一百多年都没能破解呢
That serious cops couldn't crack in a hundred years!
噢  你别说了
Oh, stop it.
杰斐逊啊
By Jefferson!
我们看起来是被困在一个类似木箱的地方了
We seem to be trapped in some sort of crate-shaped box.
这就是木箱  总统先生
It's a crate, Mr. President.
好消息是我有总统钥匙
Good thing I have the president's key,
它能打开美国的一切锁
Which can open any lock in America.
我不觉得这会管用啊
I don't think that's gonna work.
木头  我的宿敌啊
Wood! My age-old enemy.
为了离开这儿
In order to get out of here,
我们必须想出一个史上最傻的计划
This is going to take the silliest plan ever conceived.
我觉得我知道谁能帮你
I think I know who can help you.
嗯  不如
Hmm. How about...
利用那个洞
That hole?
我们一定能穿过去
We will leap through it!
马上  马上就好了  很好
Almost. Almost there... Good...
继续推
Keep pushing.
我不确定这能管用啊
I'm not sure this is working.
相信傻气
Trust the silliness!
没关系  继续加油
Fiddlesticks! Keep going...
那是我的第三任妻子桑迪吗
Is that my third wife Sandy?
好吧  我们并没有穿过那个洞
Well, we didn't fit through the hole.
我们重新把箱子拼好再试一次吧
Let's rebuild the box and try again.
我们得离开这儿
We gotta get out of here!
也是个好主意
Also good.
布拉布斯
Blubs!
把那玩意儿给我
Give me that!
你们
There is...
无处可逃了
No escape!
我得歇一会儿
I gotta take a knee.
你还好吗  你需要我帮忙吗
Are you okay? Can I get you anything?
埃德温・杜兰德  你真是一个善良的粗人
Edwin Durland, you are a diamond in the rough.
布拉布斯警官  你真的想把我们锁在
Sheriff Blubs, do you really want to lock us all up
某个政府机构里吗
in a government facility somewhere?
我没有其他选择
I've got no choice!
我们接受来自最高层的命令
Our orders come from the very top!
等等
Wait!
昆廷  你签署过正式的辞呈吗
Quentin, did you ever sign an official resignation?
没有  先生  我吃了一条火蜥蜴后就跳窗了
No, sir. I ate a salamander and jumped out the window.
那么严格说来你仍然是合法的
Then technically you're still legally
美国总统  对吗
The president of the United States, right?
你们现在得听他的了
You've gotta answer this guy now!
作为这个合众国的总统
As president of these several United States,
我特此命令你们假装这一切从来没有发生过
I hereby order you to pretend none of this ever happened.
然后愉快地去度个假
And go on a delightful vacation.
噢  没错
Ow! Yes.
度假吗
Vacation?
你一直想去什么地方呢
What place have you always wanted to visit?
一个  两个
One, two...
在密歇根的大湖里很傻很有趣的水上滑梯
Silly water fun slides in Grand Lakes, Michigan!
拜拜  拜
Bye-bye! Bye!
你为你的祖国作出了杰出贡献  梅宝
You've done a great service to your country, Mabel.
作为答谢  我想任命你为正式的美国国会议员
As thanks, I'd like to make you an official U.S. congressman.
我要将一切合法化
I'm legalizing everything!
-至于罗德里克  -呃  其实
-And Roderick... -Uh, actually...
你  我亲爱的孩子  正走在解开
You, dear boy, are on your way to unlocking
这片伟大土地上所有神秘事件的道路上
The mysteries of this great land,
所以我想将我的总统钥匙赠予你
So I'd like you to have my president's key.
然后他拿着船桨
And then he chased me around and
追着我打了大概三个小时
spanked me with a paddle for, like, three hours.
乔治・华盛顿是个混蛋
George Washington was a jerk.
我同意
Agreed.
把她从队伍里赶出去
Kick her off the team.
嘿  帕西菲卡  我揭开了一个政府阴谋
Hey, Pacifica! I uncovered a government conspiracy
是关于美国第八任半总统的
About the eighth-and-a-half president of the United States!
现在是谁傻啊
Who's silly now?
什么  那傻瓜是谁啊
What? Who is that idiot?
伸出你的拳头  你这个秃顶魔王
Put up your dukes, you bald fiend!
他是美国第八任半总统
The eighth-and-a-half president of America.
我知道你在想什么  他怎么会还活着呢
I know what you are thingking. How is he still alive?
好吧  其实你可以在花生硬糖里冬眠然后
Well, turns out you can hibernate in peanut brittle and it...
哈哈哈  哇  你真是一个可怜的小笨女孩儿
Ha ha ha! Wow! You really are a sad, dumb little girl.
顺便说一句  礼帽不错
Nice top hat, by the way.
哈哈哈哈  哈哈  说得好  女儿
Ha ha ha ha! Ha ha! Good one, daughter.
噢  我看见你家的车卡在泥巴里了
Ooh! I see your car is stuck in the mud.
祝你走回家愉快
Enjoy walking home.
难道你不准备告诉她  她那个什么曾曾祖父的事情
Aren't you gonna tell her about her ate-gray ampa-gray?
你知道吗  迪普  我不想证明任何事
You know what, Dipper? I've got nothing to prove.
我已经学会把傻气看作帅气了
I've learned to see silly as awesome!
好吧  但我什么都没学到
Well, I haven't learned anything!
嘿  帕西菲卡
Hey, Pacifica!
纳撒尼尔・诺斯维斯特并没有创建重力泉
Nathaniel Northwest didn't found Gravity Falls,
你们全家都是冒牌货
And your whole family is a sham.
好好看看吧
Deal with it!
什么  妈妈
What?! Mom!!!
天哪  我低估了复仇的滋味
Man, revenge is underrated.
感觉太爽了
That felt awesome!
孩子们  还有其他的地方需要我
Children, I am needed elsewhere.
你们只要记住我永远都会在这儿
Just know that i'll always be right here...
负十二美元钞票上
On the negative twelve dollar bill.
这根本就不值钱
This is worthless.
可不仅仅是不值钱而已  我的孩子
It's less then worthless, my boy.
特朗布莱去也
Trembley away!
你觉得他会去哪儿
Where do you think he's going?
我觉得  掉下悬崖吧
I'm gonna say... Off a cliff.
接着苏斯路过  跟我聊了大概一个小时
And then Soos came by and talked to me for like an hour.
你受了太多的苦
You've been through so much.
管用耶
It works!
-那顶礼帽是怎么回事  -我是一名国会议员
-So what's with the top hat? -I am a congressman.
-再说一遍  -你被正式宽恕了
-Pardon me? -You are officially pardoned.
噢  你永远正经不起来  对吗  孩子
Oy! You a never gonna make sense, are you, kid?
是的  斯坦叔公
No, I'm not, Grunkle Stan.
是的  我正经不了
No, I'm not.
梅宝去也
Mabel away!
我没事
I'm okay!
尊敬的美国最高法院的先生们
Esteemed gentlemen of the United States supreme court
我恳求你们重新考虑你们的决定
I implore you to rethink your decision!
很好  但是你们想让谁代替我呢
Very well. But who would you have replace me?
妈妈
Mama.
那个老太婆吗
That old crone?!
爸爸爸
Ba ba ba...
南姆南姆首席大法官  你正朝自己吐唾沫呢
Chief Justice Num-num, you're spitting up on yourself!
现在  噢  噢  别这样
Now... Ohh! Oh, come on!
这里是法庭  我
This is a courtroom! I...
这  这真是
This... This is a...
这真是美国黑暗的一天啊
This is a dark day for America.